Guide to the E. F. Craven Company Records, 1793-1991 and undated, bulk 1907-1965
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
E. F. Craven Company records 1793-1991 and undated bulk 1907-1965
E. F. Craven Co.
42 linear feet Extent: Approximately 33,750 Items
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Durham, North Carolina 27708-0185
RL.00353
Language: English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In addition, all or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. There may be a 48-hour delay in obtaining these materials.
Also, some of the materials in this collection are not immediately accessible, because they require further processing before use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The E. F. Craven Company Records were donated to the Manuscript Department in 1978 by Franklin Duval Craven, the son of Eli Franklin Craven. Mr. Craven also provided support for the processing of the collection.
Biographical Note
1907 Eli Franklin Craven sold road building machinery built by various manufacturers
1918 Craven built his first office building (13,000 square feet) on Morehead Avenue in Greensboro, NC
1925 Craven built larger three-story building adjoining his existing one and facing on Elm Street
1926 Craven incorporated his business as E. F. Craven Company. His son Franklin Duval Craven began working for him as a salesman
1964 F. Duval Craven became President of the company after his father's death
Nov. 1975 E. F. Craven Company was sold to Brocar, Inc., retaining same officers and employees. Company's name changed to EFC Associates, Inc.
1978 F. Duval Craven retired
1993 Mar. 30 Death of F. Duval Craven
Although Eli Franklin Craven founded the company named for him, the Craven family's involvement in the sale of road-building machinery began with his father Eli Asbury Craven (1824-1912). The elder Craven, a Methodist minister, sold farm and road machinery in Causey, NC before 1895. Around the turn of the century, both he and his son represented Acme Road Machinery, a company based in Frankfort, New York. Eli F. Craven sold machines produced by other companies as well, including Studebaker Brothers, Russell Grader Manufacturing Company, and John Deere Plow Company. Soon he became known to his customers as "E. F. Craven, the Road Machinery Man."
Craven's business flourished after the 1921 issuance of North Carolina's first road bonds. In 1926, after the incorporation of the company, Craven changed the slogan to "E. F. Craven Company, the Road Machinery Men," and sales totalled over $1,000,000.00. Eli Franklin Craven was manager. His son, F. Duval Craven, worked for the company as a salesperson.
During the 1940's, Franklin Duval Craven took an increasingly active role in the management of the company. Duval served as General Manager by 1948. At his father's death in 1964, he became the president of E. F. Craven Company. At this time, his brother Edwin Asbury Craven (1909-1966) was Vice-President and Treasurer. In 1977, F. Duval Craven gave up many of the operating responsibilities of the company. Charles A. Hines, Jr. became President and Chief Operating Officer.
In November 1975, F. Duval Craven sold the company to John J. Brogan of West Chatham, Massachusetts and Charles C. Carson of New York City (Brocar, Inc.), who changed the name to EFC Associates. The company retained the same officers and staff.
Collection Overview
The E. F. Craven Company Records document the development of a North Carolina road machinery dealership from a small family business into a multi-million dollar corporation. The material spans the years from 1793 to 1991; the bulk of the collection is dated 1907-1965.
Much of the material in the early years of the Correspondence Series consists of communication to and from equipment dealers and customers concerning the sale and repair of road machinery. The Cravens usually included information on the health and activities of family members in their business letters to each other. E. A. Craven frequently offered financial and spiritual advice to his son, writing his responses on the back of his son's letters to him, so that the letter and the reply appear on opposite sides of the same page. Between December 1912 and January 1916 there is a considerable amount of correspondence between family members regarding the execution of Eli A. Craven's will. Many letters written between 1907 and 1930 are written on stationery illustrated with detailed renderings of various types of early road-building equipment.
From the late 1920's until the 1940's, Franklin Duval Craven ran the Asheville office of E. F. Craven Company, frequently travelling on sales trips. E. F. Craven often wrote encouraging his son in his work and giving him advice on sales strategy. Letters from E. A. Craven and E. F. Craven reflect the deep religious beliefs of the two men and the importance they placed in conducting their lives and their business in a moral fashion.
During World War II, several of the company's employees served in the armed forces. Duval Craven corresponded frequently with them, and copies of his letters and their replies can be found among the correspondence from the war years.
As the organizational structure of the company increased in complexity, the amount of family correspondence in the collection decreased. Interoffice communications comprise a large amount of the correspondence after the 1960's.
The files in the Legal Papers, Financial Records, and Directors' Minutes Series combine to form a profile of the E. F. Craven Company: its sales, expansions, customer base, and its staff and leaders. Of particular interest is its relationship with the NC Highway Commission and state officials. Early materials in the Legal Papers Series relate to the business and land-holding activities of the Craven family in the late 19th and early 20th centuries.
Among the items in the Printed Materials Series is a nearly complete run of The Road Machinery News, a serial published by E. F. Craven Company from 1925 until 1978. This newsletter contained news about road construction, information and advertisements regarding road building machinery, and a column "A Line or Two," written by E. F. Craven. In these editorials, Craven expressed his moral and spiritual philosophies. The articles were compiled in 1975 and published as a volume entitled A Line or Two. Educational material on general sales techniques published in 1928 and 1929 is also included in the Printed Materials Series. These books and pamphlets were used in the hiring and training of E. F. Craven Company sales staff.
The Visual Materials Series includes photographs, silent motion picture films, and illustrated trade catalogs demonstrating the attributes of road construction machinery and road-building techniques of the early twentieth century. Use copies must be made of moving images before content can be accessed. Please contact the Research Services staff before coming to use this series.
Both Eli F. Craven and Eli A. Craven became members of the Religious Society of Friends (Quakers) in the 1890's. Occasional references to the Craven family's support of the Society of Friends are found in documents throughout the collection. Items specifically concerned with the Religious Society of Friends are grouped in the Subject Files under the same name.
Subject Headings
E. F. Craven Company; Craven, Eli Franklin, 1875-1964; Craven, Eli Asbury, 1824-1912; Craven, F. Duval (Franklin Duval), 1906-1993; EFC Associates, Inc.; Society of Friends -- North Carolina; Road machinery; Construction equipment; Road construction equipment industry -- History; Road construction -- North Carolina -- History; Selling; Earthmoving machinery; Road machinery -- Trade and manufacture; Corporations -- North Carolina -- History -- 20th century; Business records; Family corporations -- North Carolina; Children's writings, American; Road construction -- Equipment and supplies
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence Series, 1866-1991 and undated, bulk 1907-1952, (28 containers)
  Consists of letters and copies of letters to and from the Cravens, their employees, and their business associates. Arranged chronologically by year. In years for which a large amount of correspondence exists, the letters are arranged in one to six-month increments. Includes two letter copy books containing letters written by Eli A. Craven and Eli Franklin Craven between 1901 and 1905.
  - 1866-1906, April, (5 folders) (Box 1)
  - 1906, April-1907, March 23, (5 folders) (Box 2)
  - 1907, March 24- Sept., (6 folders) (Box 3)
  - 1907, Oct.-1908, Apr., (8 folders) (Box 4)
  - 1908, May-Sept., (8 folders) (Box 5)
  - 1908, Oct.-1909, Oct., (7 folders) (Box 6)
  - 1909, Nov.-1910, June, (6 folders) (Box 7)
  - 1910, July-Dec., (7 folders) (Box 8)
  - 1911, Jan.-Mar., (4 folders) (Box 9)
  - 1911, Apr.-June, (4 folders) (Box 10)
  - 1911, July-1912, Feb., (7 folders) (Box 11)
  - 1912, Mar.-1914, Mar., (6 folders) (Box 12)
  - 1914, Apr.-1915, Nov. 15, (6 folders) (Box 13)
  - 1915, Nov. 16-Dec., (6 folders) (Box 14)
  - 1917, Jan.-1928, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 15)
  - 1929, Jan.-1930, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 16)
  - 1931, Jan.-1933, Apr., (8 folders) (Box 17)
  - 1933, May-1934, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 18)
  - 1935, Jan.-1936, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 19)
  - 1937, Jan.-1941, Dec., (7 folders) (Box 20)
  - 1942, Jan.-1944, Dec., (6 folders) (Box 21)
  - 1945, Jan.-1947, (4 folders) (Box 22)
  - 1948, Jan.-1955, (8 folders) (Box 23)
  - 1956-1965, (9 folders) (Box 24)
  - 1966, Jan.-1969, (7 folders) (Box 25)
  - 1970-1974, (7 folders) (Box 26)
  - 1975, Jan.-1979, (7 folders) (Box 27)
  - 1980-1991, n.d., (8 folders) (Box 28)
  - Vol. No. 1 Letter copy book, 1901-1903 (contains vol. 1) (Box 29)
  - Vol. No. 2 Letter copy book, 1904-1905 (contains vol. 2) (Box 30)
- Financial Records Series, 1855-1985 and undated, bulk 1900-1975, (81 containers) (Box 30)
  Includes statements, invoices, reports, tax forms, cancelled stock certificates, and payroll records. Most of the items were generated by the E. F. Craven Company and its suppliers. Arranged chronologically by year. Refer to container list for description of volumes. See oversize material as well.
  - 1884-1915, (8 folders) (Box 31)
  - 1916-1925, (8 folders) (Box 32)
  - 1926-1939, (6 folders) (Box 33)
  - 1940-1965, (6 folders) (Box 34)
  - 1966-1976, (5 folders) (Box 35)
  - 1977-1985, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 36)
  - Price lists from Acme Road Machinery Co., n.d. (Box 36)
  - Stock stubs and certificates (Box 37)
  - Vol. No. 3 Account Book, 1855-1868 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 4 Account Book, 1872-1878 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 5 Sales Book, 1892 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 6 Cash Book, 1897-1913 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 7 Bankbook: Greensboro National Bank, 1899-1901 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 8 Sales Comparison Book, 1907-1929 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 9 Cash Book, 1915-1926 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 10 Bankbook, 1917-1923 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 11 Account Book, 1920-1924 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 12 Expense Book, 1924-1926 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 13 Audit Report, 1924-1925 (Box 38 (contains vols. 3-13))
  - Vol. No. 14 Payroll Book, 1926-1935 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 15 Expense Book, May 1927 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 16 Expense Book, July 1927 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 17 Expense Book, July 1927 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 18 Cash Journal, 1927-1928 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 19 Sales Comparison Book, 1927 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 20 Schedule of Rental & Depreciation of Construction Equipment, 1928 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 21 Ledger, 1928 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 22 Account Book, 1929 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 23 Schedule of Rental & Depreciation of Construction Equipment, 1930-1939 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 24 Order Book, 1933 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 25 Order Book, 1936 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 26 Record of Tax-Deductible Business Expenditures, 1937-1941 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 27 Cash Book, 1941-1943 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 28 Cash Book, 1944-1946 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 29 Sales Book, 1946-1947 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 30 Sales Book, 1947-1949 (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 31 Bills Payable & Bills Receivable, 1921, Aug.-1925, Aug. (Box 39 (contains vols. 14-31))
  - Vol. No. 32 Stock Ledger, 1927-1982 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Vol. No. 33 Account Book, 1910-1918 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Vol. No. 34 Account Book, 1910-1917 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Vol. No. 35 Cash Book, 1975-1982 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Vol. No. 36 Appraisal Report, 1981, Aug. 31 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Vol. No. 37 Appraisal Report, 1981, Sept. 1 (Box 40 (contains vols. 32-37))
  - Order books, 1910-1917, (28 items) (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 38 Order Book, 1917, Jan.-1918, June (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 39 Order Book, 1918, June-1919, Dec. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 40 Order Book, 1920, Jan.-Sept. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 41 Order Book, 1922, Aug. 27-1924, Jan. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 42 Order Book, 1924, Jan.-1925, Mar. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 43 Order Book, 1925, Mar.-1926, Apr. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 44 Order Book, 1926, Apr.-1927, June (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 45 Order Book, 1927, June-1928, Nov. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 46 Order Book, 1928, Nov.-1930, July (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 47 Order Book, 1930, July-1932 Nov. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 48 Order Book, 1932, Nov.-1934, Dec. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 49 Notes and Bills Receivable and Payable, 1921-1922 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 50 Bills Receivable, 1925-1927 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 51 Notes and Bills Receivable, 1925-1928 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 52 Factory Invoice Records, 1922, Aug.-1924, Mar. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 53 Factory Invoice Records, 1924, Feb.-1925, July (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 54 Factory Invoice Records, 1925, July-1926, July (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 55 Ledger, 1913-1917, May (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 56 Ledger, 1917, Apr.-1919, Jan. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 57 Cash Journal, 1920, Jan.-1922, Apr. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 58 Cash Journal, 1922, May-1923, Feb. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 59 Cash Journal and Daily Financial Statement, 1922, Mar.-1925, Dec. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 60 Equipment Sales and Ownership Record, 1927 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 61 Factory Invoice Records, 1926, June-1926, Sept. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 62 Equipment Sales and Ownership Record, 1917-1927 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 63 Ledger, 1910-1915 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 64 Equipment Ownership Record, 1921-1927 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 65 Cash Receipt Journal, 1918-1919 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 66 Cash Receipt Journal, 1920-August 1922 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 67 Cash Receipt Journal, 1922-1923 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 68 Record of Sales by Individuals 1921-1926 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 69 Account Journal, 1921, Oct.-1923, Feb. (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 70 Record of Paid Freight Bills, 1922-1925 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 71 Monthly Balances on Open Accounts, 1925-1926 (Box 41)
  - Vol. No. 72 Monthly Balances and Payments on Open Accounts, 1927-1928 (Box 41)
- Legal Papers, 1793-1983 and undated, bulk 1910-1983, (3 containers) (Box 41)
  Early legal papers consist of land transactions, property inventories, summonses, and wills. Among the other items are contracts between E. F. Craven Company and various manufacturers of road machinery regarding the sale of their products; documents regarding the 1968 controversy over the North Carolina Highway Commission's specifications for road machinery; the 1974 merger agreement between E. F. Craven Company and Pitt Realty Corporation; and the 1975 purchase agreement between E. F. Craven Company and Brocar, Incorporated. Arranged chronologically by year.
  - Papers, 1793-1965, (6 folders) (Box 42)
  - N.C. Highway Commission, 1966-1967 (Box 43)
  - Papers, 1968-1974 (Box 43)
  - Motor Grader Hearing, 1968, Jan. 19-1968, Mar. 5, (4 folders) (Box 43)
  - Pitt-Craven Merger, 1974, (7 folders) (Box 43)
  - Purchase agreement, 1975, Nov. 14, (2 folders) (Box 44)
  - Lease agreement, 1975, Nov. 14 (Box 44)
  - Papers, 1975-1978 (Box 44)
  - D & L Limited Partnership Closing Documents, 1982, Nov. 15 (Box 44)
  - Papers, 1982-1983, n.d. (Box 44)
- Directors' Minutes Series, 1926-1983, (2 containers) (Box 44)
  Includes a copy of the Certificate of Incorporation and the by-laws of E. F. Craven Company as well as a continuous run of the minutes of the Board of Directors from 1926-1983. Arranged chronologically.
  - Directors' Minutes, 1926-1974, (7 folders) (Box 45)
  - Directors' Minutes, 1975-1983, (8 folders) (Box 46)
- Visual Materials Series, 1901-1980 and undated, (5 containers) (Box 46)
  Photographs, demonstration catalogs, and 16mm. motion picture films of machinery sold by E. F. Craven Company; photographs of the Craven family and company employees; and pictures of the E. F. Craven Company buildings and construction sites comprise this series.
  Arranged in three general categories: Machinery (subdivided alphabetically by manufacturer), People, and Places. Items are arranged chronologically by year within these categories with some exceptions being made due to housing constraints. Refer to the container list for descriptions of films and volumes. Also see oversize material.
  [Originals of films are closed to use. Technical Services staff need to arrange for use copies to be made before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
  - Machinery Subseries (Box 46)
    - Photographs (Box 46)
      - Allis-Chalmers, 1930-1989, n.d., (3 folders) (Box 47)
      - Best-Midget, 1920-1977, n.d. (Box 47)
      - Bucyrus Erie, 1930-1979, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 47)
      - Peerless-Russell, 1932-1977, n.d. (Box 48)
      - Russell Manufacturing Catalog Pages, ca. 1918, (3 folders) (Box 48)
      - Sandusky, Unidentified, 1920-1977, n.d. (Box 48)
      - Unidentified and miscellaneous, 1920-1980, n.d. (Box 48)
    - Albums (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 73 Littleford Tar and Asphalt Heaters Photographic Catalog, n.d. (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 74 Allis-Chalmers Manufacturing Catalog, 1928-1929 (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 75 Erie Shovel Catalog, n.d. (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 76 Frank G. Hough Company Album, n.d. (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 77 Universal Crane Catalog, ca. 1920 (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
      - Vol. No. 78 Parsons Company Catalog, ca. 1920 (Box 49 (contains vols. 73-78))
    - Film Reels (Box 50)
      [Original films are closed to use. Technical Services staff need to arrange for use copies to be made before contents can be accessed. Please contact Research Services staff before coming to use the collection.]
      - 1. Russell Grader with Caterpillar tractor and Adams back-sloper attachment, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 2. Terracing with county maintenance equipment (Allis-Chalmers HD7 Diesel 22 Tractor) in Texas, Missouri, Oklahoma, and Iowa, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 3. American Asphalt Company loading rock and sand with Haiss loaders in Chicago, Illinois, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 4. How to Build a Modern Mixed-In-Place Road Surface Written text gives step-by-step explanation. Littleford Distributor and Littleford Bituminous Resurfacer, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 5. Machinery not identified. Dated 6/15/1928. Road construction; in Raleigh, NC. (Box 50)
      - 6. Haiss Excavator. Digging wet clay and macadam. Filmed in Illinois and at the state capitol grounds in Olympia, WA, ca. 1927. (Box 50)
      - 7. Haiss Excavator. Loading sand and rock in Chicago, IL and Rockville, NY, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 8. Haiss excavation and concrete pouring. Digging subway under Illinois Central Station, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 9. Tractor pulling trees. Machinery not identified, n.d. (Box 50)
      - 10. Haiss creeper, grader, and loader. Late 1920's. (Box 50)
      - 11. Adams grader and back-sloper with leaning wheel, 1928. (Box 50)
      - 12. Bucyrus-Erie Steam Shovel. Excavating underground in some shots, n.d. (Box 50)
  - People Subseries (Box 50)
    - Photographs, 1901-1989, n.d., (4 folders) (Box 51)
    - Oversize photographs, 1920s, n.d. (Box 65 (2nd 70:H))
  - Places Subseries (Box 65 (2nd 70:H))
    - 1900-1978, n.d., (2 folders) (Box 51)
- Printed Materials Series, 1880-1990 and undated, bulk 1907-1990, (7 containers) (Box 51)
  Consists of unused stationery, serials, advertisements, catalogs, and pamphlets produced by E. F. Craven Company and machinery companies with whom they did business as well as articles and a book written by Eli Franklin Craven. Includes clippings of articles about E. F. Craven Company and the Craven family. See container list for description of volumes.
  - Serials (Box 52)
    - Road Machinery News: (Box 52)
      - Introduction, 1983, Aug. 25 (Box 52)
      - 1925, Mar.-1960, Nov., (12 folders) (Box 52)
  - Serials (Box 53)
    - Road Machinery News: (Box 53)
      - 1960-1978, Jan., (6 folders) (Box 53)
    - Baker, Bucyeus-Erie, Enginews, Russell News (Box 53)
  - Catalogs: (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 79 E. F. Craven Company Catalog, 1943-1944 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 80 E. F. Craven Company Catalog, 1953 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 81 E. F. Craven Company Catalog, 1973 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 82 Allis-Chalmers United Tractor Catalog, 1930 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 83 Allis-Chalmers Ind"U"strial Catalog, 1930 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 84 Rawlings Implement Company Catalog, 1916 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 85 Russell Grader Repair Parts Catalog, n.d. (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 86 Russell Grader Manufacturing Company Catalog, 1926-1927 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 87 Russell Grader Manufacturing Company Catalog, 1914 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
    - Vol. No. 88 John Deere Plow Company Catalog, 1916 (Box 54 (contains vols. 79-88))
  - Catalogs: (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
    - Vol. No. 89 Stag Manganese Steel Catalog, n.d. (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
    - Vol. No. 90 Acme Road Machinery Company Price List, 1900-1910 (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
    - Vol. No. 91 E. F. Craven Company Catalog, 1924-1926 (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
    - Vol. No. 92 Powers Highway Catalog and Directory, 1932 (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
    - Vol. No. 93 Western Wheeled Scraper Company Catalog, ca. 1927 (Box 55 (contains vols. 89-93))
  - Catalogs: (Box 56 (contains vols. 94-95))
    - Vol. No. 94 Earth Mover, 1927 (Box 56 (contains vols. 94-95))
    - Vol. No. 95 Earth Mover, 1928 (Box 56 (contains vols. 94-95))
    - "Practical Selling" pamphlets, 1929 (Box 57 (contains vols. 96-97))
    - Sales Training notebook, 1922-1977 (Box 57 (contains vols. 96-97))
    - Vol. No. 96 Illustrated Selling, 1928 (Box 57 (contains vols. 96-97))
    - Vol. No. 97 A Line or Two, 1975 (Box 57 (contains vols. 96-97))
    - Allis-Chalmers catalogs and literature, 1930s-1950s (Box 72)
  - Advertising, stationery, etc., 1880-1990, n.d., (6 folders) (Box 58)
  - Clippings, 1913, Jan. 15-1986, July, n.d. (Box 58)
- Subject Files Series, 1852-1987, (1 container) (Box 58)